Rinat Abdrashitov

rinat.abdras@gmail.com | +1-647-295-1387 | Toronto, ON, Canada www.dgp.toronto.edu/~rinat | github.com/rin-23

ABOUT

Computer graphics engineer and researcher with over three years experience working in industry and publications in top graphics venues. Experienced in designing and implementing algorithms for solving **3D geometry processing** problems as well as strong **C++** and **GPU** programming skills. Experienced in developing **iOS** apps using **Objective-C**, **UIKit**, and **OpenGL ES**.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Ph.D. candidate, Computer Science Master of Science, Computer Science Honors Bachelor of Computer Science with Distinction Toronto, Canada 01/2016 – 06/2021 (expected) 09/2013 – 01/2015 09/2008 – 06/2012

EXPERIENCE

SideFX Software

Toronto, Canada

Research Engineer

intern 05/2019 – 02/2020, part-time 02/2020 - current

- Designed and implemented a non-rigid surface registration algorithm to deform mesh templates to fit partial, incomplete, and noisy **3D mesh scans**.
- Wrote a production-quality nonlinear least squares solver, using C++ and Eigen, for the core optimization problem, while ensuring speed, robustness, and numerical accuracy.
- Implemented the results of the work using **C++** and **Python** and integrated it into Houdini 18.5 (TopoTransfer Node) which is an industry-standard software used in film, TV, and video games.

University of Toronto

Toronto, Canada

Ph.D. Student (Advisor: Professor Karan Singh)

01/2016 – 04/2021(expected)

- Performed research in novel interactive techniques for 3D modeling, face animation, and fabrication.
- Solved complex **3D geometry** problems on triangular meshes like segmentation, smoothing, deformation, reconstruction and gained experience in applying **linear algebra** and numerical **optimization** to solve **math computational** problems.
- Used C++, Python, and OpenGL to develop interactive research prototypes from scratch.
- Results were published at the top computer graphics and HCI conferences (see publications).

Conceptualiz Inc.

Toronto, Canada 02/2015 – 01/2016

Research Engineer

- Built an iPad application from the ground up that allows orthopedic surgeons to perform pre-operative planning in a 3D environment using patient-specific CT scan data.
- Developed a custom real-time rendering engine, using **OpenGL ES, GLSL, and C++**, to render high-resolution polygonal models of bone tissue on a mobile **GPU**.
- Gained experience with software design patterns while developing a set of interactive tools for creating implant models to reflect the workflow of orthopedic surgeons.
- The app was successfully released on the **App Store** under the name of Ossa3D and it's the first app

of its kind available on tablet devices.

XtremeLabs Inc. (acquired by Pivotal Software Inc.)

Software Developer

Toronto, Canada 09/2012 – 09/2013

- Developed high profile **iOS** applications starting from the concept to submitting the finished product to the **App Store**. Clients included Bell, Mountain Equipment Co-op, and The Globe and Mail.
- Gained experience in object oriented programming using Objective-C and Cocoa toolkit.
- Worked effectively with the QA team to resolve any technical issues and bugs.

RESEARCH INTERNSHIPS

Adobe Research San Jose, CA

Research Intern

06/2017 - 08/2017

- Worked on applying 12 principles of animation to videos of human faces to achieve a stylized effect.
- Used face landmark detection algorithms to extract landmark coordinates over time and used Python to write image warping and signal processing algorithms to generate cartoonish stylized results.
- The results of the research were patented (See patents).

PUBLICATIONS

Interactive Modelling of Volumetric Musculoskeletal Anatomy.

Under review

Rinat Abdrashitov, Seungbae Bang, Alec Jacobson, David Levin, Karan Singh

Interactive exploration and refinement of facial expression using manifold learning.

UIST 2020

Rinat Abdrashitov, Fanny Chevalier, Karan Singh

A System for Efficient 3D Printed Stop-Motion Face Animation.

SIGGRAPH 2020

Rinat Abdrashitov, Alec Jacobson, Karan Singh

Interactive Shape Modeling using a Skeleton-Mesh Co-Representation.

SIGGRAPH 2014

J. Andreas Bærentzen, Rinat Abdrashitov, Karan Singh.

Mosaic: Sketch-based interface for creating digital decorative mosaics.

SBIM 2014

Rinat Abdrashitov, Eric Yao, Emilie Guy, Karan Singh.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C++, C, Python

Numerics: MATLAB, NumPy, SciPy, Eigen

GPU: OpenGL, GLSL

Machine Learning: PyTorch, Linear Algebra, Calculus, Convex Optimization

Software: Maya C++/Python API, Houdini, LibIGL

PATENTS

Reducing collision-based defects in motion-stylization of video content depicting closely spaced features (US Patent granted 2019)

Rinat Abdrashitov, Jose Ignacio Echevarria Vallespi, Jingwan Lu, Elya Shectman, Duygu Ceylan Aksit, David Simons